<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scheduler on Han&#39;s XYZ</title>
    <link>https://han8931.github.io/tags/scheduler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scheduler on Han&#39;s XYZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:39:28 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://han8931.github.io/tags/scheduler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manage your task with TaskSpooler!</title>
      <link>https://han8931.github.io/taskspooler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</author>
      <guid>https://han8931.github.io/taskspooler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-taskspooler&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/justanhduc/task-spooler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;TaskSpooler&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/justanhduc/task-spooler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;TaskSpooler&lt;/a&gt; (ts) is a lightweight job scheduler that allows you to queue up your tasks and execute them in order. It’s particularly useful for environments where tasks need to be managed sequentially or with a controlled degree of parallelism. Unlike more complex systems like SLURM, TaskSpooler is designed for simplicity and ease of use, making it accessible for individual researchers and small teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficient-job-scheduling-for-mldl-researchers-with-taskspooler&#34;&gt;Efficient Job Scheduling for ML/DL Researchers with Taskspooler&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the dynamic field of Machine Learning (ML) and Deep Learning (DL), managing and optimizing computational resources is crucial. For researchers frequently running numerous experiments, an efficient job scheduler can be a game-changer. Enter &lt;strong&gt;Taskspooler&lt;/strong&gt;, a powerful yet user-friendly job scheduler for Linux, designed to help you manage and schedule your jobs in a queue. Taskspooler is a simpler alternative to SLURM, providing many benefits for ML/DL researchers, especially when it comes to utilizing GPUs efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
