<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Han&#39;s XYZ</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Han&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Getting Started with Regression: An Introductory Guide (Part 1)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240810_regression/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240810_regression/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Getting Started with Regression: An Introductory Guide (Part 1) Inline Formula: {{&lt; raw &gt;}}(\mathbf{E}=\sum_{i} \mathbf{E}{i}=\mathbf{E}{1}+\mathbf{E}{2}+\mathbf{E}{3}+\cdots){{&lt; /raw &gt;}} (\mathbf{x})
(\mathbf{x})
[ a=b+c \ d+e=f ] Block Formula:
{{&lt; raw &gt;}} [ a=b+c \ d+e=f ] {{&lt; /raw &gt;}}
Raw content using Markdown syntax: {{&lt; raw &gt;}}Hello{{&lt; /raw &gt;}}
\begin{align} 1+2 \end{align}
$$1+2$$
Regression is a method used to identify the relationship between input and output variables. In a regression problem, we are given a set of noisy measurements (or output data) $\mathbf{y} = [y_1, \dots, y_d]^T$, which are affected by measurement noise $\boldsymbol{\eta} = [\eta_1, \dots, \eta_d]^T$.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Encryption using GPG!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240804_gpg_encryption/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240804_gpg_encryption/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Securing Your Privacy The importance of securing your data has become critical in the modern digital era. This post explores a versatile tool called GnuPG, or GNU Privacy Guard, which allows you to encrypt your data and communications, ensuring that only the intended recipients can access them.
Asymmetric Encryption Before looking at GPG, let’s first review some encryption approaches. A very naive approach to sharing encrypted files is to use the same secret key between a sender and a receiver.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Manage your task with TaskSpooler!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240713_taskspooler/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240713_taskspooler/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is TaskSpooler ? TaskSpooler (ts) is a lightweight job scheduler that allows you to queue up your tasks and execute them in order. It’s particularly useful for environments where tasks need to be managed sequentially or with a controlled degree of parallelism. Unlike more complex systems like SLURM, TaskSpooler is designed for simplicity and ease of use, making it accessible for individual researchers and small teams.
Efficient Job Scheduling for ML/DL Researchers with Taskspooler In the dynamic field of Machine Learning (ML) and Deep Learning (DL), managing and optimizing computational resources is crucial.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Dependency Management in Python</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240707_poetry/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240707_poetry/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Poetry is a dependency management and packaging tool in Python, aiming to improve how you define, install, and manage project dependencies.
Installation: You can install Poetry through its custom installer script or using package managers. The recommended way is to use their installer script to ensure you get the latest version. Creating a New Project: Use poetry new &lt;project-name&gt; to create a new project with a standard layout. Adding Dependencies: Add new dependencies directly to your project using poetry add &lt;package&gt;.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Handy Pacman Commands in Arch Linux</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240501_pacman/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240501_pacman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Pacman , the package manager for Arch Linux, is known for its simple binary package format and easy-to-use build system . The primary aim of Pacman is to facilitate straightforward management of packages from both the official repositories and user-generated builds.
Pacman ensures your system remains updated by synchronizing the package lists with the master server. This client/server model simplifies the process of downloading and installing packages, along with all their dependencies, using basic commands.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Vim, Type at the Speed of Thought!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240501_vim/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240501_vim/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[While it may look somewhat obsolete in an era dominated by graphically rich IDEs, Vim remains not just a highly relevant and effective tool for today&rsquo;s programmers but also a badge of coolness in the tech world. Those who master its commands are often seen as coding wizards. With its unique advantages in speed, efficiency, and customizability, Vim is an invaluable asset in software development environments, proving that old-school can still be trendy.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why Use Python&#39;s `pdb` Debugger Over an IDE?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pdb/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pdb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When it comes to debugging Python code, most programmers reach for an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) because of its convenience and powerful features. However, there&rsquo;s a classic, built-in tool that shouldn&rsquo;t be overlooked: Python&rsquo;s own debugger, pdb. This tool might seem basic at first glance, but it offers some compelling advantages, especially in scenarios where an IDE might be less effective. Here&rsquo;s why you might consider using pdb for debugging your Python projects:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data validation with Pydantic!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pydantic/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pydantic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Python&rsquo;s dynamic typing system is indeed convenient, allowing you to create variables without explicitly declaring their types. While this flexibility can streamline development, it can also introduce unexpected behavior, particularly when handling data from external sources like APIs or user input.
Consider the following scenario:
1 2 employee = Employee(&#34;Han&#34;, 30) # Correct employee = Employee(&#34;Moon&#34;, &#34;30&#34;) # Correct Here, the second argument is intended to represent an age, typically an integer.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Enumerate variables with Enum!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_enum/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_enum/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Enum is a way that Python enumerate variables. The enum module allows for the creation of enumerated constants—unique, immutable data types that are useful for representing a fixed set of values. These values, which are usually related by their context, are known as enumeration members.
Enum provides&hellip;
Uniqueness - Each member of an Enum is unique within its definition, meaning no two members can have the same value. Attempting to define two members with the same value will result in an error unless you explicitly allow aliases.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Unit Test with Pytest</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_unit-tests/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_unit-tests/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Unit testing involves testing individual components of software in isolation to ensure they function correctly. Automated frameworks facilitate this process, which is integral to ensuring that new changes do not disrupt existing functionality. Unit tests also serve as practical documentation and encourage better software design. This testing method boosts development speed and confidence by confirming component reliability before integration. Early bug detection through unit testing also helps minimize future repair costs and efforts.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
