<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Han&#39;s XYZ</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Han&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>tabularasa8931@gmail.com (Han)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Handy Pacman Commands in Arch Linux</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240501_pacman/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240501_pacman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Pacman , the package manager for Arch Linux, is known for its simple binary package format and easy-to-use build system . The primary aim of Pacman is to facilitate straightforward management of packages from both the official repositories and user-generated builds.
Pacman ensures your system remains updated by synchronizing the package lists with the master server. This client/server model simplifies the process of downloading and installing packages, along with all their dependencies, using basic commands.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Type at the speed of thought!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240501_vim/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240501_vim/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[While it may look somewhat obsolete in an era dominated by graphically rich IDEs, Vim remains not just a highly relevant and effective tool for today&rsquo;s programmers but also a badge of coolness in the tech world. Those who master its commands are often seen as coding wizards. With its unique advantages in speed, efficiency, and customizability, Vim is an invaluable asset in software development environments, proving that old-school can still be trendy.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why Use Python&#39;s `pdb` Debugger Over an IDE?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pdb/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pdb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When it comes to debugging Python code, most programmers reach for an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) because of its convenience and powerful features. However, there&rsquo;s a classic, built-in tool that shouldn&rsquo;t be overlooked: Python&rsquo;s own debugger, pdb. This tool might seem basic at first glance, but it offers some compelling advantages, especially in scenarios where an IDE might be less effective. Here&rsquo;s why you might consider using pdb for debugging your Python projects:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data validation with Pydantic!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pydantic/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_pydantic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Python&rsquo;s dynamic typing system is indeed convenient, allowing you to create variables without explicitly declaring their types. While this flexibility can streamline development, it can also introduce unexpected behavior, particularly when handling data from external sources like APIs or user input.
Consider the following scenario:
1 2 employee = Employee(&#34;Han&#34;, 30) # Correct employee = Employee(&#34;Moon&#34;, &#34;30&#34;) # Correct Here, the second argument is intended to represent an age, typically an integer.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Enumerate variables with Enum!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_enum/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_enum/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Enum is a way that Python enumerate variables. The enum module allows for the creation of enumerated constants—unique, immutable data types that are useful for representing a fixed set of values. These values, which are usually related by their context, are known as enumeration members.
Enum provides&hellip;
Uniqueness - Each member of an Enum is unique within its definition, meaning no two members can have the same value. Attempting to define two members with the same value will result in an error unless you explicitly allow aliases.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Unit Test with Pytest</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240426_unit-tests/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240426_unit-tests/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Unit testing involves testing individual components of software in isolation to ensure they function correctly. Automated frameworks facilitate this process, which is integral to ensuring that new changes do not disrupt existing functionality. Unit tests also serve as practical documentation and encourage better software design. This testing method boosts development speed and confidence by confirming component reliability before integration. Early bug detection through unit testing also helps minimize future repair costs and efforts.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Bash script tutorial</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240421_the-shell-script-tutorial/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240421_the-shell-script-tutorial/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Let&rsquo;s create our first simple shell script
1 2 3 #!/bin/sh # This is a comment! echo Hello World # This is a comment, too! The first line tells Unix that the file is to be executed by /bin/sh. This is the standard location of the Bourne shell on just about every Unix system. If you&rsquo;re using GNU/Linux, /bin/sh is normally a symbolic link to bash (or, more recently, dash). The second line begins with a special symbol: #.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Minimalism Through Linux</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240421_why-linux/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240421_why-linux/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Linux, A Path to Digital Simplicity In an age dominated by digital clutter and overwhelming software choices, the minimalist philosophy stands out as a beacon for those seeking simplicity and efficiency. This approach not only applies to physical possessions but extends into the digital realm, where Linux has become a preferred tool for minimalists.
Linux, an open-source operating system, embodies the principles of minimalism by offering users control over their digital environments.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to keep sensitive data in Python?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240421_hide-sensitive-data/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240421_hide-sensitive-data/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An app&rsquo;s config is everything that is likely to vary between deploys (staging, production, developer environments, etc). This includes:
Resource handles to the database, Memcached, and other backing services Credentials to external services such as Amazon S3 or Twitter Per-deploy values such as the canonical hostname for the deploy Apps sometimes store config as constants in the code. This is a violation of twelve-factor, which requires strict separation of config from code.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Type hint in Python</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/20240421_type-hint/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Han</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/20240421_type-hint/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Type hinting is not mandatory, but it can make your code easier to understand and debug by
Improved readability Better IDE support: IDEs and linters can use type hints to check your code for potential errors before runtime. While type hints can be simple classes like float or str , they can also be more complex. The typing module provides a vocabulary of more advanced type hints.
Basics 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 # This is how you declare the type of a variable age: int = 1 # You don&#39;t need to initialize a variable to annotate it a: int # Ok (no value at runtime until assigned) # Doing so can be useful in conditional branches child: bool if age &lt; 18: child = True else: child = False 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 x: int = 1 x: float = 1.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
